{"tagSpace":{"note":"This is the top level tag,\n          used (by the tagging system) to describe the properties of the dataset","fieldTypes":[{"fieldTypes":[{"fieldTypes":[{"values":[{"note":"The data contain deidentified information from patient records related to substance abuse diagnosis, referral, or treatment","name":"deidentified","ordinal":0},{"note":"The data contain identifying information about substance abuse treatment that was released from US Veterans Affairs or Armed Services medical records","name":"veteransMedicalData","ordinal":1},{"note":"The data contain identifying information about substance abuse treatment from records disclosed with the consent of the patient","name":"consent","ordinal":2},{"note":"The data contain identifiable information about substance abuse treatment from records disclosed under the scientific research exception to the substance abuse confidentiality regulations","name":"scientificResearch","ordinal":3}],"name":"Part2","type":"AtomicType"},{"values":[{"note":"The data contain identifiable health information disclosed with waiver or alteration of authorization by an IRB or Privacy Board","name":"waiver","ordinal":0},{"note":"The data contain identifiable health information disclosed for limited purposes with patient authorization","name":"authorization","ordinal":1},{"note":"The data contain health information that have been deidentified according to the HIPAA Privacy Rule safe harbor standard","name":"safeHarborDeidentified","ordinal":2},{"note":"The data contain health information that have been deidentified using the HIPAA Privacy Rule expert determination method","name":"expertDetermination","ordinal":3},{"note":"The data contain identifiable health information disclosed as a limited data set under the HIPAA Privacy Rule","name":"limitedDataset","ordinal":4},{"note":"The data contain identifiable health information disclosed pursuant to a HIPAA business associate contract","name":"businessAssociateContract","ordinal":5}],"name":"HIPAA","type":"AggregateType"}],"name":"MedicalRecords","type":"CompoundType"},{"fieldTypes":[{"values":[{"note":"The data contain deidentified education records as defined in FERPA","name":"deidentified","ordinal":0},{"note":"The data contain directory information from students who have requested to opt out of the disclosure of this information","name":"directoryOptOut","ordinal":1},{"note":"The data contain identifiable information from education records designated by an educational agency or institution as directory information","name":"directoryInfo","ordinal":2},{"note":"The data contain identifiable information from education records disclosed under the school official exception to FERPA","name":"schoolOfficial","ordinal":3},{"note":"The data contain identifiable information from education records disclosed under the studies exception to FERPA","name":"study","ordinal":4},{"note":"The data contain identifiable information from education records disclosed with the consent of the parents or students","name":"consent","ordinal":5},{"note":"The data contain identifiable information from education records disclosed under the audit or evaluation exception to FERPA","name":"audit","ordinal":6}],"name":"FERPA","type":"AggregateType"},{"values":[{"note":"The data contain identifiable information that falls within one of the 8 categories of sensitive information protected under the PPRA","name":"protected","ordinal":0},{"note":"The data contain deidentified information that falls within one of the 8 categories of sensitive information protected under the PPRA","name":"protectedDeidentified","ordinal":1},{"note":"The data were collected with the prior written consent of the parents, or adult or emancipated minor students","name":"consent","ordinal":2},{"note":"The data were collected after providing parents with notice and an opportunity to opt out of the collection and disclosure of the information","name":"optOutProvided","ordinal":3},{"note":"The data contain personal information collected from students for the purpose of marketing or sale","name":"marketing","ordinal":4}],"name":"PPRA","type":"AggregateType"}],"name":"EducationRecords","type":"CompoundType"},{"values":[{"note":"Use or sharing of the data is not restricted by a contract or policy","name":"no","ordinal":0},{"note":"Use or sharing of the data is restricted by a contract or policy","name":"yes","ordinal":1}],"name":"ContractOrPolicy","type":"AtomicType"},{"fieldTypes":[{"values":[{"name":"highlyRestricted","ordinal":0},{"name":"required","ordinal":1},{"name":"stateConsentLimited","ordinal":2},{"name":"stateConsentBroad","ordinal":3},{"name":"requesterConsentLimited","ordinal":4},{"name":"requesterConsentBroad","ordinal":5},{"name":"research","ordinal":6},{"name":"exception","ordinal":7}],"name":"DPPA","type":"AggregateType"},{"values":[{"name":"deidentified","ordinal":0},{"name":"identifiable","ordinal":1}],"name":"CIPSEA","type":"AggregateType"},{"values":[{"name":"deidentified","ordinal":0},{"name":"identifiable","ordinal":1}],"name":"PrivacyAct","type":"AggregateType"},{"values":[{"name":"CensusPublished","ordinal":0}],"name":"Census","type":"AggregateType"},{"values":[{"name":"restricted","ordinal":0},{"name":"public","ordinal":1}],"name":"ESRA","type":"AggregateType"}],"name":"GovernmentRecords","type":"CompoundType"}],"name":"Legal","type":"CompoundType"},{"fieldTypes":[{"fieldTypes":[{"values":[{"name":"noRisk","ordinal":0},{"name":"minimal","ordinal":1},{"name":"shame","ordinal":2},{"name":"civil","ordinal":3},{"name":"criminal","ordinal":4},{"name":"maxControl","ordinal":5}],"name":"Harm","type":"AtomicType"},{"values":[{"name":"anonymous","ordinal":0},{"name":"deidentified","ordinal":1},{"name":"identifiable","ordinal":2},{"name":"identified","ordinal":3}],"name":"Effort","type":"AtomicType"}],"name":"DataType","type":"CompoundType"},{"note":"Assertions pertaining to intellectual property","name":"IP","type":"ToDoType"},{"values":[{"note":"Data is about inanimate objects","name":"noPersonData","ordinal":0},{"note":"Data is about living people, but in aggregated form - where aggregation is over a group large enough","name":"notPersonSpecific","ordinal":1},{"note":"Personal information can be directly inferred from the data","name":"personSpecific","ordinal":2}],"name":"Identity","type":"AtomicType"}],"name":"Assertions","type":"CompoundType"},{"note":"practical and applicable aspects of data handling","fieldTypes":[{"values":[{"note":"Available to anonymous individuals.","name":"None","ordinal":0},{"note":"Available to individuals with verified email address.","name":"Email","ordinal":1},{"note":"Available to individuals with verified online identity or a mobile phone.","name":"OAuth","ordinal":2},{"note":"Available to individuals having a password accounts on system.","name":"Password","ordinal":3}],"name":"Authentication","type":"AggregateType"},{"values":[{"name":"None","ordinal":0},{"name":"Email","ordinal":1},{"name":"Signed","ordinal":2}],"name":"Approval","type":"AtomicType"},{"note":"How the dataset should be transmitted","values":[{"note":"No encryption involved.","name":"clear","ordinal":0},{"note":"Single encryption.","name":"encrypt","ordinal":1},{"note":"Encryption with two keys, which may be held by different parties.","name":"doubleEncrypt","ordinal":2}],"name":"Transit","type":"AtomicType"},{"note":"The way data are stored on the server.","values":[{"note":"Not encrypted at all","name":"clear","ordinal":0},{"note":"Encryption on the server, \"at rest\". Attacker cannot use the data by getting the files from the file system","name":"serverEncrypt","ordinal":1},{"note":"Encryption on the client side. Data obtained from the server (e.g. buy data breach or subpeona)\n                  cannot be used unless the depositor provides the password","name":"clientEncrypt","ordinal":2},{"note":"Encryption on the client, and then on the server. Both passwords are required in order to make use of the data","name":"doubleEncrypt","ordinal":3}],"name":"Storage","type":"AtomicType"},{"values":[{"name":"approval","ordinal":0},{"name":"none","ordinal":1}],"name":"auth","type":"AtomicType"},{"values":[{"name":"Click","ordinal":0},{"name":"Signed","ordinal":1},{"name":"SignWithID","ordinal":2}],"name":"Acceptance","type":"AtomicType"},{"fieldTypes":[{"values":[{"name":"NoRestriction","ordinal":0},{"name":"Research","ordinal":1},{"name":"IRB","ordinal":2},{"name":"NoProduct","ordinal":3}],"name":"Use","type":"AtomicType"},{"values":[{"name":"NoRestriction","ordinal":0},{"name":"Notify","ordinal":1},{"name":"PreApprove","ordinal":2},{"name":"Prohibited","ordinal":3}],"name":"Publication","type":"AtomicType"},{"note":"Under what condition may the data user reidentify the human subjects","values":[{"name":"NoMatching","ordinal":0},{"name":"NoEntities","ordinal":1},{"name":"NoPeople","ordinal":2},{"name":"NoProhibition","ordinal":3},{"name":"Reidentify","ordinal":4},{"name":"Contact","ordinal":5}],"name":"Reidentify","type":"AtomicType"},{"values":[{"note":"Data stored indefinitely","name":"none","ordinal":0},{"note":"Data will be deleted after 50 years","name":"_50yr","ordinal":1},{"note":"Data will be deleted after 5 years","name":"_5yr","ordinal":2},{"note":"Data will be deleted after 2 years","name":"_2yr","ordinal":3},{"note":"Data will be deleted after 1 years","name":"_1yr","ordinal":4}],"name":"TimeLimit","type":"AtomicType"},{"values":[{"name":"Anyone","ordinal":0},{"name":"NotOnline","ordinal":1},{"name":"Organization","ordinal":2},{"name":"Group","ordinal":3},{"name":"NoOne","ordinal":4}],"name":"Sharing","type":"AtomicType"},{"values":[{"name":"NotNeeded","ordinal":0},{"name":"Yearly","ordinal":1},{"name":"Monthly","ordinal":2}],"name":"Auditing","type":"AtomicType"}],"name":"DUA","type":"CompoundType"}],"name":"Handling","type":"CompoundType"},{"note":"This tag is actually going away soon, to become inferred by compliance sub-spaces (long story, read the paper when it's out)","values":[{"note":"Non-confidential information that can be stored and shared freely.","name":"blue","ordinal":0},{"note":"Potentially identifiable but not harmful personal information, shared with some access control.","name":"green","ordinal":1},{"note":"Potentially harmful personal information, shared with loosely verified and\/or approved recipients.","name":"yellow","ordinal":2},{"note":"May include sensitive, identifiable personal information, shared with verified and\/or approved recipients under agreement.","name":"orange","ordinal":3},{"note":"Very sensitive identifiable personal information, shared with strong verification of approved recipients under signed agreement.","name":"red","ordinal":4},{"note":"Requires explicit permission for each transaction, using strong verification of approved recipients under signed agreement.","name":"crimson","ordinal":5}],"name":"Code","type":"AtomicType"}],"name":"DataTags","type":"CompoundType"},"data_tag_json_version":"1.0.0","decisionGraph":{"dua":{"nodes":[{"id":"dua","text":"Data use agreements","type":"TodoNode"},{"assignments":[{"Handling":[{"DUA":[{"TimeLimit":"none"}]}]}],"id":"[#84]","type":"setNode"},{"assignments":[{"Legal":[{"ContractOrPolicy":"yes"}]}],"id":"[#90]","type":"setNode"},{"id":"[#92]","type":"EndNode"},{"assignments":[{"Legal":[{"ContractOrPolicy":"no"}]}],"id":"[#91]","type":"setNode"},{"question":"Did the data have any restrictions on sharing, e.g. stated in an agreement or policy statement?","terms":[],"answers":[{"answer_sub_graph_id":"[#90]","text":"yes"},{"answer_sub_graph_id":"[#91]","text":"no"}],"id":"duaAdditional","type":"AskNode"},{"assignments":[{"Handling":[{"DUA":[{"TimeLimit":"none"}]}]}],"id":"[#86]","type":"setNode"},{"assignments":[{"Handling":[{"DUA":[{"TimeLimit":"_50yr"}]}]}],"id":"[#87]","type":"setNode"},{"assignments":[{"Handling":[{"DUA":[{"TimeLimit":"_5yr"}]}]}],"id":"[#88]","type":"setNode"},{"assignments":[{"Handling":[{"DUA":[{"TimeLimit":"_1yr"}]}]}],"id":"[#89]","type":"setNode"},{"question":"For how long should we keep the data?","terms":[],"answers":[{"answer_sub_graph_id":"[#86]","text":"indefinitely"},{"answer_sub_graph_id":"[#87]","text":"50 years"},{"answer_sub_graph_id":"[#88]","text":"5 years"},{"answer_sub_graph_id":"[#89]","text":"1 year"}],"id":"[#85]","type":"AskNode"},{"question":"Is there any reason why we cannot store the data indefinitely?\n\t       Limiting the time a dataset could be held interferes with good science practices such as replication, and should thus be avoided whenever possible. ","terms":[],"answers":[{"answer_sub_graph_id":"[#84]","text":"no"},{"answer_sub_graph_id":"[#85]","text":"yes"}],"id":"duaTimeLimit","type":"AskNode"}],"edges":[{"source":"dua","target":"duaTimeLimit"},{"source":"duaTimeLimit","target":"[#84]"},{"source":"[#84]","target":"duaAdditional"},{"source":"duaAdditional","target":"[#90]"},{"source":"[#90]","target":"[#92]"},{"source":"duaAdditional","target":"[#91]"},{"source":"[#91]","target":"[#92]"},{"source":"duaTimeLimit","target":"[#85]"},{"source":"[#85]","target":"[#86]"},{"source":"[#86]","target":"duaAdditional"},{"source":"[#85]","target":"[#87]"},{"source":"[#87]","target":"duaAdditional"},{"source":"[#85]","target":"[#88]"},{"source":"[#88]","target":"duaAdditional"},{"source":"[#85]","target":"[#89]"},{"source":"[#89]","target":"duaAdditional"}]},"Gov1":{"nodes":[{"assignments":[{"Legal":[{"GovernmentRecords":[{"Census":["CensusPublished"]}]}]},{"Assertions":[{"DataType":[{"Harm":"minimal"},{"Effort":"deidentified"}]}]},{"Handling":[{"Transit":"clear"},{"Storage":"clear"}]},{"Code":"green"}],"id":"[#58]","type":"setNode"},{"reason":"Possible violation of ESRA due to failure to obtain authorization to disclose the data from the Institute of Education Sciences","id":"[#61]","type":"RejectNode"},{"assignments":[{"Legal":[{"GovernmentRecords":[{"ESRA":["restricted"]}]}]},{"Assertions":[{"DataType":[{"Harm":"shame"}]}]},{"Handling":[{"Transit":"encrypt"},{"Storage":"serverEncrypt"}]},{"Code":"yellow"}],"id":"[#62]","type":"setNode"},{"assignments":[{"Legal":[{"GovernmentRecords":[{"CIPSEA":["deidentified"]}]}]}],"id":"[#64]","type":"setNode"},{"assignments":[{"Legal":[{"GovernmentRecords":[{"PrivacyAct":["identifiable"]}]}]}],"id":"[#67]","type":"setNode"},{"id":"[#68]","text":"Privacy Act DUA","type":"TodoNode"},{"id":"[#70]","type":"EndNode"},{"assignments":[{"Legal":[{"GovernmentRecords":[{"PrivacyAct":["deidentified"]}]}]}],"id":"[#69]","type":"setNode"},{"question":"Do the data contain personally identifiable information?","terms":[{"term":"Personally identifiable information","explanation":"Any information about an individual that can be used to distinguish or trace an individual's identity - such as name, address, or Social Security number - either by itself or in combination with any other information that is linked or linkable to an individual, such as medical, educational, financial, criminal or employment history."}],"answers":[{"answer_sub_graph_id":"[#67]","text":"yes"},{"answer_sub_graph_id":"[#69]","text":"no"}],"id":"PA2","type":"AskNode"},{"question":"Are the data maintained by the agency in a system of records?","terms":[{"term":"System of records","explanation":"A system of records is a group of any records under the control of any agency from which information is retrieved by the name of the individual or by some identifying number, symbol, or other identifying particular assigned to the individual."},{"term":"Record","explanation":"A record is any item, collection, or grouping of information about an individual that is maintained by an agency, including, but not limited to, his education, financial transactions, medical history, and criminal or employment history, and that contains his name, or the identifying number, symbol, or other identifying particular assigned to the individual, such as a finger or voice print or a photograph."}],"answers":[{"answer_sub_graph_id":"PA2","text":"yes"},{"answer_sub_graph_id":"[#70]","text":"no"}],"id":"PA1","type":"AskNode"},{"assignments":[{"Legal":[{"GovernmentRecords":[{"CIPSEA":["identifiable"]}]}]}],"id":"[#65]","type":"setNode"},{"id":"[#66]","text":"CIPSEA DUA","type":"TodoNode"},{"question":"Are the data being shared in identifiable form?","terms":[{"term":"Identifiable form","explanation":"Identifiable form refers to any representation of information that permits the identity of the respondent to whom the information applies to be reasonably inferred by either direct or indirect means."}],"answers":[{"answer_sub_graph_id":"[#64]","text":"no"},{"answer_sub_graph_id":"[#65]","text":"yes"}],"id":"CIPSEA3","type":"AskNode"},{"question":"Is the agency that collected the data a statistical agency or unit from this list: USDA Economic Research Service, National Agricultural Statistics Service, Bureau of Economic Analysis, Census Bureau, National Center for Education Statistics, Energy Information Administration, National Center for Health Statistics, Bureau of Justice Statistics, Bureau of Labor Statistics, Bureau of Transportation Statistics, Statistics of Income Division of the Internal Revenue Service, or NSF Division of Science Resources Statistics?","terms":[],"answers":[{"answer_sub_graph_id":"CIPSEA3","text":"yes"},{"answer_sub_graph_id":"PA1","text":"no"}],"id":"CIPSEA2","type":"AskNode"},{"question":"Were the data collected directly from respondents for exclusively statistical purposes under a pledge of confidentiality?","terms":[],"answers":[{"answer_sub_graph_id":"CIPSEA2","text":"yes"},{"answer_sub_graph_id":"PA1","text":"no"}],"id":"CIPSEA1","type":"AskNode"},{"assignments":[{"Legal":[{"GovernmentRecords":[{"ESRA":["public"]}]}]},{"Assertions":[{"DataType":[{"Harm":"minimal"}]}]},{"Handling":[{"Transit":"clear"},{"Storage":"clear"}]},{"Code":"green"}],"id":"[#63]","type":"setNode"},{"question":"Has the IES Data Security Office limited access to the data to individuals authorized by an IES license agreement or individuals who have executed an affidavit of nondisclosure?","terms":[],"answers":[{"answer_sub_graph_id":"[#62]","text":"yes"},{"answer_sub_graph_id":"[#63]","text":"no"}],"id":"ESRA3","type":"AskNode"},{"question":"Have the data been published previously, or did you submit a copy of the data to the Institute of Education Sciences (IES) Data Security Office and receive its authorization to disclose the data?","terms":[],"answers":[{"answer_sub_graph_id":"[#61]","text":"no"},{"answer_sub_graph_id":"ESRA3","text":"yes"}],"id":"ESRA2","type":"AskNode"},{"question":"Do the data contain information from an education research project that receives funding from the Institute of Education Sciences? Examples of funded projects are included \ton the following web sites:\n  \t\t\t\t* National Center for Education Research [NCER] - http:\/\/ies.ed.gov\/ncer\/projects\/\n  \t\t\t\t* National Center for Education Evaluation and Regional Assistance [NCEE] - http:\/\/ies.ed.gov\/ncee\/projects\/\n  \t\t\t\t* What Works Clearinghouse [WWC] - http:\/\/ies.ed.gov\/ncee\/wwc\/\n  \t\t\t\t* Regional Educational Laboratory Program - http:\/\/ies.ed.gov\/ncee\/edlabs\/index.asp\n  \t\t\t\t* Education Resources Information Center [ERIC] - http:\/\/ies.ed.gov\/ncee\/projects\/eric.asp\n  \t\t\t\t* National Library of Education [NLE] - http:\/\/ies.ed.gov\/ncee\/projects\/nle\/\n  \t\t\t\t* National Center for Special Education Research [NCSER] - http:\/\/ies.ed.gov\/ncser\/projects\/\n  \t\t\t\t* National Center for Education Statistics [NCES] - http:\/\/nces.ed.gov\/surveys\/","terms":[],"answers":[{"answer_sub_graph_id":"ESRA2","text":"yes"},{"answer_sub_graph_id":"CIPSEA1","text":"no"}],"id":"ESRA1","type":"AskNode"},{"assignments":[{"Legal":[{"GovernmentRecords":[{"Census":["CensusPublished"]}]}]},{"Assertions":[{"DataType":[{"Harm":"minimal"},{"Effort":"deidentified"}]}]},{"Handling":[{"Transit":"clear"},{"Storage":"clear"}]},{"Code":"green"}],"id":"[#59]","type":"setNode"},{"reason":"Possible violation of Title 13 due to failure to obtain permission from the Census Bureau to publish the Census data.","id":"[#60]","type":"RejectNode"},{"question":"Has a Census Bureau Disclosure Review Board issued an approval memorandum granting formal permission for the data to be published?","terms":[],"answers":[{"answer_sub_graph_id":"[#59]","text":"yes"},{"answer_sub_graph_id":"[#60]","text":"no"}],"id":"Census3","type":"AskNode"},{"question":"Were the data published by the Census Bureau?","terms":[],"answers":[{"answer_sub_graph_id":"[#58]","text":"yes"},{"answer_sub_graph_id":"Census3","text":"no"}],"id":"Census2","type":"AskNode"},{"question":"Were the data collected by the US Census Bureau?","terms":[],"answers":[{"answer_sub_graph_id":"Census2","text":"yes"},{"answer_sub_graph_id":"ESRA1","text":"no"}],"id":"Census1","type":"AskNode"},{"question":"Are you an employee or an agent, such as a contractor, consultant, researcher, or employee of a private organization, operating under a contract, grant, or other agreement with the agency that collected the data?","terms":[],"answers":[{"answer_sub_graph_id":"Census1","text":"yes"},{"answer_sub_graph_id":"ESRA1","text":"no"}],"id":"Gov2","type":"AskNode"},{"question":"Were the data collected by a federal agency or a researcher under contract with or with funds from a federal agency?","terms":[],"answers":[{"answer_sub_graph_id":"Gov2","text":"yes"},{"answer_sub_graph_id":"[#70]","text":"no"}],"id":"Gov1","type":"AskNode"}],"edges":[{"source":"Gov1","target":"Gov2"},{"source":"Gov2","target":"Census1"},{"source":"Census1","target":"Census2"},{"source":"Census2","target":"[#58]"},{"source":"[#58]","target":"ESRA1"},{"source":"ESRA1","target":"ESRA2"},{"source":"ESRA2","target":"[#61]"},{"source":"ESRA2","target":"ESRA3"},{"source":"ESRA3","target":"[#62]"},{"source":"[#62]","target":"CIPSEA1"},{"source":"CIPSEA1","target":"CIPSEA2"},{"source":"CIPSEA2","target":"CIPSEA3"},{"source":"CIPSEA3","target":"[#64]"},{"source":"[#64]","target":"PA1"},{"source":"PA1","target":"PA2"},{"source":"PA2","target":"[#67]"},{"source":"[#67]","target":"[#68]"},{"source":"[#68]","target":"[#70]"},{"source":"PA2","target":"[#69]"},{"source":"[#69]","target":"[#70]"},{"source":"PA1","target":"[#70]"},{"source":"CIPSEA3","target":"[#65]"},{"source":"[#65]","target":"[#66]"},{"source":"[#66]","target":"PA1"},{"source":"CIPSEA2","target":"PA1"},{"source":"CIPSEA1","target":"PA1"},{"source":"ESRA3","target":"[#63]"},{"source":"[#63]","target":"CIPSEA1"},{"source":"ESRA1","target":"CIPSEA1"},{"source":"Census2","target":"Census3"},{"source":"Census3","target":"[#59]"},{"source":"[#59]","target":"ESRA1"},{"source":"Census3","target":"[#60]"},{"source":"Census1","target":"ESRA1"},{"source":"Gov2","target":"ESRA1"},{"source":"Gov1","target":"[#70]"}]},"medicalRecordsCompliance":{"nodes":[{"id":"[#11]","type":"EndNode"},{"assignments":[{"Legal":[{"MedicalRecords":[{"Part2":"deidentified"}]}]},{"Assertions":[{"DataType":[{"Effort":"deidentified"}]}]},{"Handling":[{"Transit":"clear"},{"Storage":"clear"}]},{"Code":"green"}],"id":"[#12]","type":"setNode"},{"id":"[#17]","type":"EndNode"},{"reason":"For additional guidance on determining whether an individual or organization is a covered entity, please review the charts provided by the Centers for Medicare & Medicaid Services at\n  \t\t\t\t\t\t\thttp:\/\/www.cms.gov\/Regulations-and-Guidance\/HIPAA-Administrative-Simplification\/HIPAAGenInfo\/Downloads\/CoveredEntitycharts.pdf","id":"[#18]","type":"RejectNode"},{"assignments":[{"Legal":[{"MedicalRecords":[{"HIPAA":["safeHarborDeidentified"]}]}]},{"Assertions":[{"DataType":[{"Harm":"minimal"},{"Effort":"deidentified"}]}]},{"Handling":[{"Transit":"clear"},{"Storage":"clear"}]},{"Code":"green"}],"id":"[#19]","type":"setNode"},{"id":"[#20]","type":"EndNode"},{"assignments":[{"Legal":[{"MedicalRecords":[{"HIPAA":["expertDetermination"]}]}]},{"Assertions":[{"DataType":[{"Harm":"minimal"},{"Effort":"deidentified"}]}]},{"Handling":[{"Transit":"clear"},{"Storage":"clear"}]},{"Code":"green"}],"id":"[#21]","type":"setNode"},{"id":"[#22]","type":"EndNode"},{"assignments":[{"Legal":[{"MedicalRecords":[{"HIPAA":["limitedDataset"]}]}]},{"Assertions":[{"DataType":[{"Harm":"minimal"},{"Effort":"deidentified"}]}]},{"Handling":[{"Transit":"clear"},{"Storage":"clear"}]},{"Code":"green"}],"id":"[#23]","type":"setNode"},{"id":"[#24]","type":"EndNode"},{"assignments":[{"Legal":[{"MedicalRecords":[{"HIPAA":["authorization"]}]}]},{"Assertions":[{"DataType":[{"Harm":"civil"},{"Effort":"identifiable"}]}]},{"Handling":[{"Transit":"encrypt"},{"Storage":"serverEncrypt"}]},{"Code":"orange"}],"id":"[#25]","type":"setNode"},{"id":"[#28]","type":"EndNode"},{"assignments":[{"Legal":[{"MedicalRecords":[{"HIPAA":["waiver"]}]}]},{"Assertions":[{"DataType":[{"Harm":"civil"},{"Effort":"identifiable"}]}]},{"Handling":[{"Transit":"encrypt"},{"Storage":"serverEncrypt"}]},{"Code":"orange"}],"id":"[#26]","type":"setNode"},{"assignments":[{"Legal":[{"MedicalRecords":[{"HIPAA":["businessAssociateContract"]}]}]},{"Assertions":[{"DataType":[{"Harm":"civil"},{"Effort":"identifiable"}]}]},{"Handling":[{"Transit":"encrypt"},{"Storage":"serverEncrypt"}]},{"Code":"orange"}],"id":"[#27]","type":"setNode"},{"question":"Were the data disclosed pursuant to a HIPAA business associate contract?","terms":[{"term":"Business associate contract","explanation":"A covered entity is required to enter into a business associate contract when it discloses protected health information to a business associate, or an individual or entity providing claims processing or administration, data analysis, processing or administration, utilization review, quality assurance, or similar functions or activities on behalf of the covered entity. A covered entity may also, but is not required to, enter in such a contract when disclosing protected health information to a researcher."}],"answers":[{"answer_sub_graph_id":"[#27]","text":"yes"},{"answer_sub_graph_id":"[#28]","text":"no"}],"id":"MR13","type":"AskNode"},{"question":"Has an oversight body such as an Institutional Review Board [IRB] or Privacy Board reviewed how the data will be used or disclosed and approved a request to alter or waive the Authorization requirement?","terms":[{"term":"Privacy Board","explanation":"An alternative to an IRB, comprised of members of varying backgrounds and appropriate professional competencies as necessary to review the effect of the research protocol on individual privacy rights and related interests. Privacy Boards must have at least one member who is not affiliated with the covered entity that will use or disclose the PHI involved in the research project, not affiliated with any entity conducting or sponsoring the research, and not related to any person who is affiliated with such entities, and members may not have conflicts of interest regarding the projects they review."},{"term":"Institutional review board - IRB","explanation":"A board, committee or group formally designated by an institution to review research involving human subjects. Most universities and academic medical centers that receive federal funding often have designated IRBs."},{"term":"Alterations \/ Waivers to Authorization","explanation":"An IRB or Privacy Board may approve a waiver or alteration of the research participants\u2019 authorization for use or disclosure of information about them for research purposes. This provision can be used to conduct records research when the research could not practicably be conducted if research participants\u2019 authorization were required. A covered entity may use or disclose protected health information for research purposes pursuant to a waiver of authorization by an IRB or Privacy Board, provided it has obtained documentation describing the IRB or Privacy Board, the date of approval, a description of the information to be used or disclosed, and a statement that the use or disclosure has been reviewed and approved under either normal or expedited review procedures."}],"answers":[{"answer_sub_graph_id":"[#26]","text":"yes"},{"answer_sub_graph_id":"MR13","text":"no"}],"id":"MR12","type":"AskNode"},{"question":"Do the data contain health information from patients who have provided written authorization for their information to be disclosed to or used by third parties?","terms":[{"term":"Authorization","explanation":"Refers to an individual\u2019s signed permission to allow a covered entity to use or disclose the individual's protected health information. It includes a detailed description of the information to be used or disclosed, specific persons authorized to use or disclose the information, a description of the purpose of use or disclosure of the information, and an expiration date. Authorization may be combined with a consent to participate in the research, or with any other legal permission related to the research study."}],"answers":[{"answer_sub_graph_id":"[#25]","text":"yes"},{"answer_sub_graph_id":"MR12","text":"no"}],"id":"MR11","type":"AskNode"},{"question":"Do the data contain protected health information from medical records? In other words, do the data contain any health information that can be used to identify an individual? This includes, but is not limited to, demographic information or anything related to an individual\u2019s past, present, or future health condition and related treatments or payments.","terms":[{"term":"Individually identifiable health information","explanation":"Individually identifiable health information is information that is a subset of health information, including demographic information collected from an individual by a covered entity, that relates to an individual\u2019s past, present, or future physical or mental health condition, the provision of health care to the individual, or the past, present, or future payment for the provision of health care to the individual. It often includes common identifiers such as name, address, birth date, Social Security number, or anything that can reasonably be used to identify the individual. When information relates to an individual\u2019s past or current treatment for alcohol or drug abuse, this includes any information \u2013 recorded or unrecorded \u2013 that could be used to determine the patient\u2019s identity directly or by reference to other publicly available information."},{"term":"Protected health information","explanation":"Protected health information is defined as individually identifiable health information that is transmitted or maintained in any form of media. It excludes individually identifiable health information in education records covered by the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act [FERPA] and employment records held by a covered entity in its role as an employer."}],"answers":[{"answer_sub_graph_id":"MR11","text":"yes"},{"answer_sub_graph_id":"[#28]","text":"no"}],"id":"MR10","type":"AskNode"},{"question":"Do the data constitute a limited data set under the HIPAA Privacy Rule?","terms":[{"term":"Limited data set","explanation":"A limited data set contains patient information that has been stripped of all of the following identifiers and is shared according to the terms of a data use agreement.\n      \t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t* Names\n      \t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t* Postal address information other than city or town, state, and ZIP code\n      \t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t* Telephone or fax numbers\n      \t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t* Email addresses\n      \t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t* Social security numbers\n      \t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t* Medical record, health plan beneficiary, or other account numbers\n      \t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t* Certificate\/license numbers\n      \t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t* Vehicle identifiers or serial numbers, including license plate numbers\n      \t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t* Device identifiers or serial numbers\n      \t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t* Web universal resource locators [URLs]\n      \t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t* Internet Protocol [IP] address numbers\n      \t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t* Biometric identifiers including finger and voice prints\n      \t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t* Full face photographic images or other comparable images"}],"answers":[{"answer_sub_graph_id":"[#23]","text":"yes"},{"answer_sub_graph_id":"MR10","text":"no"}],"id":"MR9","type":"AskNode"},{"question":"Has an expert in statistical or scientific principles and methods for deidentification certified that the data have been deidentified?","terms":[{"term":"Certification","explanation":"Means the expert has applied appropriate principles and methods and determined that the risk is very small that the information could be used, alone or in combination with other reasonably available information, to identify one of the data subjects, and has documented the methods and results of the analysis justifying such determination."}],"answers":[{"answer_sub_graph_id":"[#21]","text":"yes"},{"answer_sub_graph_id":"MR9","text":"no"}],"id":"MR8a","type":"AskNode"},{"question":"Have all direct identifiers been removed from the data?","terms":[{"term":"Direct identifiers","explanation":"Refers to the following list of identifiers of the patient or of relatives, employers, or household members of the patient:\n  \t\t\t\t\t* Names\n  \t\t\t\t\t* Geographic subdivisions smaller than a state, including street address, city, county, precinct, ZIP code, and their equivalent geocodes, except for the initial three digits of the ZIP code if, (1) the geographic unit formed by combining all ZIP codes with the same three initial digits contains more than 20,000 people; and (2) the initial three digits of a ZIP code for all such geographic units containing 20,000 or fewer people is changed to 000\n  \t\t\t\t\t* All elements of dates (except year) for dates that directly relate to an individual [e.g., birth date, admission date, discharge date, death date, and all ages over 89]\n  \t\t\t\t\t* Telephone or fax numbers\n  \t\t\t\t\t* Email addresses\n  \t\t\t\t\t* Social security numbers\n  \t\t\t\t\t* Medical record, health plan beneficiary, and all other account numbers\n  \t\t\t\t\t* Certificate\/license numbers\n  \t\t\t\t\t* Vehicle identifiers and serial numbers, including license plate numbers\n  \t\t\t\t\t* Device identifiers and serial numbers\n  \t\t\t\t\t* Web universal resource locators (URLs)\n  \t\t\t\t\t* Internet Protocol [IP] address numbers\n  \t\t\t\t\t* Biometric identifiers, including finger and voice prints\n  \t\t\t\t\t* Full face photographic images and any comparable images\n  \t\t\t\t\t* Any other unique identifying number, characteristic, or code"}],"answers":[{"answer_sub_graph_id":"[#19]","text":"yes"},{"answer_sub_graph_id":"MR8a","text":"no"}],"id":"MR8","type":"AskNode"},{"question":"Do the data contain information from a covered entity or business associate of a covered entity?","terms":[{"term":"Business associate","explanation":"A business associate is any person or organization, including a subcontractor, that acts on behalf of, or provides services to, a covered entity involving the use or disclosure of protected health information. This includes, but is not limited to, legal, actuarial, accounting, consulting, claim processing, data analysis, administration, utilization review, quality assurance, billing, benefit management, practice management, and re-pricing activities."},{"term":"Covered entity","explanation":"A covered entity is a health plan, health care clearinghouse, or health care provider that transmits any health information in electronic form.\n\t\t\t* Health plans include health insurance companies, health maintenance organizations [HMOs], company health plans, and government programs that pay for health care, such as Medicare, Medicaid, and the military and veterans health care programs.\n\t\t\t* Health care providers include doctors, clinics, psychologists, dentists, chiropractors, nursing homes, and pharmacies.\n\t\t\t* Health care clearinghouses include entities that process nonstandard health information they receive from another entity into a standard, i.e. standard electronic format or data content, or vice versa."}],"answers":[{"answer_sub_graph_id":"[#17]","text":"no"},{"answer_sub_graph_id":"[#18]","text":"Not Sure"},{"answer_sub_graph_id":"MR8","text":"yes"}],"id":"MR7","type":"AskNode"},{"reason":"reject data and flag for review; possible violation of 38 U.S.C. 4132 due to the release of VA medical records without a valid exception.","id":"[#13]","type":"RejectNode"},{"assignments":[{"Legal":[{"MedicalRecords":[{"Part2":"veteransMedicalData"}]}]},{"Assertions":[{"DataType":[{"Harm":"civil"},{"Effort":"identifiable"}]}]},{"Handling":[{"Transit":"encrypt"}]},{"Code":"orange"}],"id":"[#14]","type":"setNode"},{"question":"Were the data maintained by the Department of Veterans Affairs either shared with the patients\u2019 consent for the purposes of scientific research, or shared without consent but in connection with a medical emergency or public health activity related to HIV?","terms":[],"answers":[{"answer_sub_graph_id":"[#13]","text":"no"},{"answer_sub_graph_id":"[#14]","text":"yes"}],"id":"MR4a","type":"AskNode"},{"assignments":[{"Legal":[{"MedicalRecords":[{"Part2":"consent"}]}]},{"Assertions":[{"DataType":[{"Harm":"civil"},{"Effort":"identifiable"}]}]},{"Handling":[{"Transit":"encrypt"},{"Storage":"serverEncrypt"}]},{"Code":"orange"}],"id":"[#15]","type":"setNode"},{"assignments":[{"Legal":[{"MedicalRecords":[{"Part2":"scientificResearch"}]}]},{"Assertions":[{"DataType":[{"Harm":"civil"},{"Effort":"identifiable"}]}]},{"Handling":[{"Transit":"encrypt"},{"Storage":"serverEncrypt"}]},{"Code":"orange"}],"id":"[#16]","type":"setNode"},{"question":"Were the data shared by the substance abuse program for scientific research purposes?","terms":[{"term":"Scientific research purposes","explanation":"This refers to information from substance abuse patient records disclosed for the purpose of conducting scientific research. The director of the substance abuse program may decide to release information for this purpose if he or she determines that the recipient of the patient identifiable information is qualified to conduct the research and has a research protocol under which the information will be maintained in accordance with specific security requirements under the substance abuse confidentiality regulations"}],"answers":[{"answer_sub_graph_id":"[#16]","text":"yes"},{"answer_sub_graph_id":"MR7","text":"no"}],"id":"MR6","type":"AskNode"},{"question":"Did the individuals provide written consent for the disclosure of their information?","terms":[{"term":"Written consent","explanation":"Includes the specific name or a designation of the program or person permitted to disclose the information; the name or title of the individual or the name of the organization to which disclosure is to be made; the name of the patient; the purpose of the disclosure; how much and what kind of information is to be disclosed; the signature of the patient, or a person authorized to sign on behalf of the patient; and the date on which the consent is signed."}],"answers":[{"answer_sub_graph_id":"[#15]","text":"yes"},{"answer_sub_graph_id":"MR6","text":"no"}],"id":"MR5","type":"AskNode"},{"question":"Were the data maintained in connection with the US Department of Veterans Affairs or US Armed Services?","terms":[],"answers":[{"answer_sub_graph_id":"MR4a","text":"yes"},{"answer_sub_graph_id":"MR5","text":"no"}],"id":"MR4","type":"AskNode"},{"question":"Do any of the substance abuse records contain patient identifying information, or information that would identify a patient as an alcohol or drug abuser either directly or by reference to other publicly available information?","terms":[{"term":"Patient identifying information","explanation":"This means the name, address, Social Security number, fingerprints, photograph, or similar information by which the identity of a patient can be determined with reasonable accuracy and speed either directly or by reference to other publicly available information. The term does not include a number assigned to a patient by a program, if that number does not consist of, or contain numbers, such as a Social Security, or driver\u2019s license number, which could be used to identify a patient with reasonable accuracy and speed from sources external to the program."}],"answers":[{"answer_sub_graph_id":"[#12]","text":"no"},{"answer_sub_graph_id":"MR4","text":"yes"}],"id":"MR3","type":"AskNode"},{"question":"Were the data obtained from a federally assisted drug abuse program after March 20, 1972, or a federally assisted alcohol abuse program after May 13, 1974 (or if obtained before the pertinent date, were they maintained by a federally assisted alcohol or drug abuse program after that date as part of an ongoing treatment episode which extended past that date)?","terms":[{"term":"Federally assisted drug or alcohol abuse programs","explanation":"An alcohol or drug abuse program is considered to be federally assisted if it is conducted by any federal agency or department, whether in whole or in part, directly or by contract. This includes programs carried out under a license, certification, registration, or authorization granted by a federal department or agency. Also included are programs that receive funding from any federal department or agency, programs conducted by a state or local government that receives any form of federal financial assistance, programs carried out under certification of provider status under the Medicare program, or programs that are allowed income tax deductions for contributions to the program or are granted tax exempt status by the Internal Revenue Service."}],"answers":[{"answer_sub_graph_id":"MR3","text":"yes"},{"answer_sub_graph_id":"MR7","text":"no"}],"id":"MR2a","type":"AskNode"},{"question":"Do the data contain information related to substance abuse diagnosis, referral, or treatment?","terms":[{"term":"Information related to substance abuse diagnosis, referral, or treatment","explanation":"Any information, including information on referral and intake, about alcohol and drug abuse patients obtained by a program, such as a treatment or rehabilitation program, employee assistance program, program within a general hospital, school-based program, or a private practitioner that holds itself out as providing alcohol or drug abuse diagnosis, treatment, or referral for treatment.  This does not include emergency room services related to an apparent overdose, unless the primary function of this emergency room service is providing diagnosis, treatment or referral for alcohol or drug abuse."}],"answers":[{"answer_sub_graph_id":"MR2a","text":"yes"},{"answer_sub_graph_id":"MR7","text":"no"}],"id":"MR2","type":"AskNode"},{"question":"Do the data contain health or medical information?","terms":[],"answers":[{"answer_sub_graph_id":"[#11]","text":"no"},{"answer_sub_graph_id":"MR2","text":"yes"}],"id":"medicalRecordsCompliance","type":"AskNode"}],"edges":[{"source":"medicalRecordsCompliance","target":"[#11]"},{"source":"medicalRecordsCompliance","target":"MR2"},{"source":"MR2","target":"MR2a"},{"source":"MR2a","target":"MR3"},{"source":"MR3","target":"[#12]"},{"source":"[#12]","target":"MR7"},{"source":"MR7","target":"[#17]"},{"source":"MR7","target":"[#18]"},{"source":"MR7","target":"MR8"},{"source":"MR8","target":"[#19]"},{"source":"[#19]","target":"[#20]"},{"source":"MR8","target":"MR8a"},{"source":"MR8a","target":"[#21]"},{"source":"[#21]","target":"[#22]"},{"source":"MR8a","target":"MR9"},{"source":"MR9","target":"[#23]"},{"source":"[#23]","target":"[#24]"},{"source":"MR9","target":"MR10"},{"source":"MR10","target":"MR11"},{"source":"MR11","target":"[#25]"},{"source":"[#25]","target":"[#28]"},{"source":"MR11","target":"MR12"},{"source":"MR12","target":"[#26]"},{"source":"[#26]","target":"[#28]"},{"source":"MR12","target":"MR13"},{"source":"MR13","target":"[#27]"},{"source":"[#27]","target":"[#28]"},{"source":"MR13","target":"[#28]"},{"source":"MR10","target":"[#28]"},{"source":"MR3","target":"MR4"},{"source":"MR4","target":"MR4a"},{"source":"MR4a","target":"[#13]"},{"source":"MR4a","target":"[#14]"},{"source":"[#14]","target":"MR7"},{"source":"MR4","target":"MR5"},{"source":"MR5","target":"[#15]"},{"source":"[#15]","target":"MR7"},{"source":"MR5","target":"MR6"},{"source":"MR6","target":"[#16]"},{"source":"[#16]","target":"MR7"},{"source":"MR6","target":"MR7"},{"source":"MR2a","target":"MR7"},{"source":"MR2","target":"MR7"}]},"$startNode":"[#1]","ppraCompliance":{"nodes":[{"id":"[#29]","type":"EndNode"},{"assignments":[{"Legal":[{"EducationRecords":[{"PPRA":["protected"]}]}]},{"Assertions":[{"DataType":[{"Harm":"civil"},{"Effort":"identifiable"}]}]},{"Handling":[{"Transit":"encrypt"},{"Storage":"serverEncrypt"}]},{"Code":"orange"}],"id":"[#30]","type":"setNode"},{"assignments":[{"Legal":[{"EducationRecords":[{"PPRA":["consent"]}]}]}],"id":"[#32]","type":"setNode"},{"id":"[#33]","type":"EndNode"},{"reason":"Possible PPRA violation due to failure to obtain written consent for collection of information protected under the PPRA","id":"[#34]","type":"RejectNode"},{"reason":"Please ask the party that collected the data whether written consent from the parents was obtained. Dataset cannot be accepted without clarifying this issue.","id":"[#35]","type":"RejectNode"},{"question":"Was written consent obtained from the parents of the students who participated in the survey or assessment, or from the students themselves if they are adults or emancipated minors, prior to the data collection?","terms":[],"answers":[{"answer_sub_graph_id":"[#32]","text":"yes"},{"answer_sub_graph_id":"[#34]","text":"no"},{"answer_sub_graph_id":"[#35]","text":"Not Sure"}],"id":"ppra4","type":"AskNode"},{"assignments":[{"Legal":[{"EducationRecords":[{"PPRA":["marketing"]}]}]}],"id":"[#36]","type":"setNode"},{"reason":"Possible PPRA violation due to school\u2019s failure to provide parents with the opportunity to opt out of the data collection","id":"[#37]","type":"RejectNode"},{"assignments":[{"Legal":[{"EducationRecords":[{"PPRA":["optOutProvided"]}]}]}],"id":"[#38]","type":"setNode"},{"id":"[#39]","type":"EndNode"},{"question":"Were parents provided with notice and an opportunity to opt out of the collection and disclosure of the information?","terms":[],"answers":[{"answer_sub_graph_id":"[#37]","text":"no"},{"answer_sub_graph_id":"[#38]","text":"yes"}],"id":"ppra7","type":"AskNode"},{"question":"Does the school in which the information was collected receive any funds from the US Department of Education?","terms":[{"term":"Funds from the US Department of Education","explanation":"This means funds provided for any purpose by the US Department of Education to the elementary or secondary school in which the data were collected. It includes any funds provided by grant, cooperative agreement, contract, sub-grant, or subcontract to the institution. The funds, alternatively, may have been provided to students attending the institution. For instance, the funds may have been paid to the institution by those students for educational purposes, such as under the Pell Grant Program and the Guaranteed Student Loan Program. Note that all public schools receive such funds, though most private and parochial schools at the elementary and secondary levels do not receive such funding."}],"answers":[{"answer_sub_graph_id":"ppra7","text":"yes"},{"answer_sub_graph_id":"[#39]","text":"no"}],"id":"ppra6","type":"AskNode"},{"question":"Was any of the personal information in the data collected from students for the purpose of marketing or sale?","terms":[{"term":"Personal Information","explanation":"Refers to individually identifiable information including, but not limited to:\n      * a student or parent\u2019s first and last name,\n      * a home or other physical address, including street name and the name of the city or town,\n      * a telephone number, or\n      * a Social Security identification number."},{"term":"Marketing Purpose","explanation":"This does not include the gathering and release of information for the following activities:\n      * College, post-secondary education, or military recruitment\n      * Book clubs, magazines, and low-cost literacy products\n      * Curriculum and instructional materials used by elementary and secondary schools\n      * Certain tests and assessments used by elementary and secondary schools\n      * Sale by students of services and products for education or school-related, fundraising activities\n      * Student recognition programs"}],"answers":[{"answer_sub_graph_id":"[#36]","text":"yes"},{"answer_sub_graph_id":"ppra6","text":"no"}],"id":"ppra5","type":"AskNode"},{"question":"Was the survey or assessment funded, in whole or in part, by the US Department of Education?","terms":[{"term":"Funded by the US Department of Education","explanation":"This means the survey or assessment received funds for any purpose from the US Department of Education. It includes any funds provided by grant, cooperative agreement, contract, sub-grant, or subcontract to the program or institution that conducted the data collection."}],"answers":[{"answer_sub_graph_id":"ppra4","text":"yes"},{"answer_sub_graph_id":"ppra5","text":"no"}],"id":"ppra3","type":"AskNode"},{"assignments":[{"Legal":[{"EducationRecords":[{"PPRA":["protectedDeidentified"]}]}]},{"Assertions":[{"DataType":[{"Harm":"minimal"},{"Effort":"deidentified"}]}]},{"Handling":[{"Transit":"clear"},{"Storage":"clear"}]},{"Code":"green"}],"id":"[#31]","type":"setNode"},{"question":"Do the data from the survey or assessment contain any personally identifiable information about a student? Personally identifiable information about a student includes, but is not limited to, the following categories of information:\n        * A student\u2019s name\n        * The name of a student\u2019s parent or other family members\n        * The address of a student or a student\u2019s family\n        * Other direct identifiers, defined as information that relates specifically to an individual, such as a student\u2019s Social Security number, student number, other identifying number or code, telephone number, e-mail address, or biometric record\n        * Other indirect identifiers defined as information that can be combined with other information to identify specific individuals, such as the student\u2019s gender, race, religion, date of birth, place of birth, other geographic indicator, weight, mother\u2019s maiden name, activities, employment information, education information, financial information, and other descriptors\n        * Other information that, alone or in combination, is linked or linkable to a specific student that would allow a reasonable person in the school community, who does not have personal knowledge of the relevant circumstances, to identify the student with reasonable certainty\n        * Information disclosed in response to a targeted request","terms":[{"term":"Targeted request","explanation":"Refers to a request by a person who the educational agency or institution reasonably believes knows the identity of the student to whom the education record relates. For example, if there was a rumor published in the local paper that a public official was disciplined for cheating during his senior year in high school, a request to the high school for the disciplinary records of students who were caught cheating during the year the public official was a senior would be considered a targeted request."},{"term":"Biometric record","explanation":"Refers to a record of one or more measurable biological or behavioral characteristics that can be used for automated recognition of an individual. Examples include fingerprints; retina and iris patterns; voiceprints; DNA sequence; facial characteristics; and handwriting."},{"term":"Deidentified information","explanation":"Information that has been deidentified is considered not to contain personally identifiable information. The term deidentified is used to describe records that have enough personally identifiable information removed or obscured such that the remaining information does not identify an individual and there is no reasonable basis to believe that the information can be used to identify an individual. In making a determination that a student\u2019s identity is not personally identifiable, both single and multiple data releases from the education records should be taken into account along with other information available from other sources."}],"answers":[{"answer_sub_graph_id":"[#30]","text":"yes"},{"answer_sub_graph_id":"[#31]","text":"no"}],"id":"ppra2a","type":"AskNode"},{"question":"Do the data contain information collected from students in a survey or assessment concerning any of the following eight categories?\n          * Political affiliations or beliefs of a student or a student\u2019s parents;\n          * Mental or psychological problems of a student or a student\u2019s family;\n          * Sex behavior or attitudes;\n          * Illegal, anti-social, self-incriminating, or demeaning behavior;\n          * Critical appraisals of other individuals with whom respondents have close family relationships;\n          * Legally recognized privileged or analogous relationships, such as those of lawyers, physicians, or members of the clergy;\n          * Religious practices, affiliations, or beliefs of a student or a student\u2019s parent; or\n          * Income, other than that required by law to determine eligibility for participation in a program or for receiving financial assistance under such program.","terms":[{"term":"Survey or assessment","explanation":"Refers to any academic or non-academic survey, assessment, analysis, or evaluation.\n                         It also includes any psychiatric or psychological examination, test, or treatment that is designed to\n                         elicit information about attitudes, habits, traits, opinions, beliefs or feelings and is not directly\n                         related to academic instruction."}],"answers":[{"answer_sub_graph_id":"ppra2a","text":"yes"},{"answer_sub_graph_id":"ppra5","text":"no"}],"id":"ppra2","type":"AskNode"},{"question":"Do the data contain any information collected from students in an elementary or secondary school?","terms":[{"term":"Elementary or secondary school","explanation":"Refers to a public or private institution in the United States providing educational services or instruction to students in any of the grades from kindergarten through high school."}],"answers":[{"answer_sub_graph_id":"[#29]","text":"no"},{"answer_sub_graph_id":"ppra2","text":"yes"}],"id":"ppraCompliance","type":"AskNode"}],"edges":[{"source":"ppraCompliance","target":"[#29]"},{"source":"ppraCompliance","target":"ppra2"},{"source":"ppra2","target":"ppra2a"},{"source":"ppra2a","target":"[#30]"},{"source":"[#30]","target":"ppra3"},{"source":"ppra3","target":"ppra4"},{"source":"ppra4","target":"[#32]"},{"source":"[#32]","target":"[#33]"},{"source":"ppra4","target":"[#34]"},{"source":"ppra4","target":"[#35]"},{"source":"ppra3","target":"ppra5"},{"source":"ppra5","target":"[#36]"},{"source":"[#36]","target":"ppra6"},{"source":"ppra6","target":"ppra7"},{"source":"ppra7","target":"[#37]"},{"source":"ppra7","target":"[#38]"},{"source":"[#38]","target":"[#39]"},{"source":"ppra6","target":"[#39]"},{"source":"ppra5","target":"ppra6"},{"source":"ppra2a","target":"[#31]"},{"source":"[#31]","target":"ppra3"},{"source":"ppra2","target":"ppra5"}]},"DPPA1":{"nodes":[{"assignments":[{"Legal":[{"GovernmentRecords":[{"DPPA":["highlyRestricted"]}]}]},{"Assertions":[{"DataType":[{"Harm":"civil"},{"Effort":"identifiable"}]}]},{"Handling":[{"Transit":"encrypt"},{"Storage":"serverEncrypt"}]},{"Code":"orange"}],"id":"[#71]","type":"setNode"},{"id":"[#83]","type":"EndNode"},{"reason":"Possible violation of the DPPA due to disclosure of highly restricted personal information without the consent of the individuals in the data","id":"[#72]","type":"RejectNode"},{"question":"Has express consent been obtained from each person whose photograph, Social Security number, or medical or disability information appears in the data?","terms":[],"answers":[{"answer_sub_graph_id":"[#71]","text":"yes"},{"answer_sub_graph_id":"[#72]","text":"no"}],"id":"DPPA2a","type":"AskNode"},{"assignments":[{"Assertions":[{"DataType":[{"Harm":"shame"},{"Effort":"identifiable"}]}]},{"Handling":[{"Transit":"encrypt"},{"Storage":"serverEncrypt"}]},{"Code":"yellow"}],"id":"[#73]","type":"setNode"},{"assignments":[{"Legal":[{"GovernmentRecords":[{"DPPA":["required"]}]}]}],"id":"[#74]","type":"setNode"},{"reason":"Possible violation of state law on disclosure of drivers' records","id":"[#75]","type":"RejectNode"},{"assignments":[{"Legal":[{"GovernmentRecords":[{"DPPA":["stateConsentLimited"]}]}]}],"id":"[#76]","type":"setNode"},{"assignments":[{"Legal":[{"GovernmentRecords":[{"DPPA":["stateConsentBroad"]}]}]}],"id":"[#77]","type":"setNode"},{"question":"Was the obtained consent limited in any way, such as purpose, duration, parties that may receive the data?","terms":[],"answers":[{"answer_sub_graph_id":"[#76]","text":"yes"},{"answer_sub_graph_id":"[#77]","text":"no"}],"id":"DPPA5a","type":"AskNode"},{"assignments":[{"Legal":[{"GovernmentRecords":[{"DPPA":["requesterConsentLimited"]}]}]}],"id":"[#78]","type":"setNode"},{"assignments":[{"Legal":[{"GovernmentRecords":[{"DPPA":["requesterConsentBroad"]}]}]}],"id":"[#79]","type":"setNode"},{"question":"Was the obtained consent limited in any way, such as purpose, duration, parties that may receive the data?","terms":[],"answers":[{"answer_sub_graph_id":"[#78]","text":"yes"},{"answer_sub_graph_id":"[#79]","text":"no"}],"id":"DPPA6a","type":"AskNode"},{"assignments":[{"Legal":[{"GovernmentRecords":[{"DPPA":["research"]}]}]}],"id":"[#80]","type":"setNode"},{"assignments":[{"Legal":[{"GovernmentRecords":[{"DPPA":["exception"]}]}]}],"id":"[#81]","type":"setNode"},{"reason":"possible violation of the DPPA because the depositor has not cited one of the required or permissible uses for disclosure.","id":"[#82]","type":"RejectNode"},{"question":"Was the personal information obtained under one of the other fourteen permissible uses for the disclosure of drivers' records, including:\n            \t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t* for use by any government agency, or any person acting on behalf of a government agency, in carrying out its functions;\n            \t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t* for use in connection with matters of motor vehicle or driver safety and theft; motor vehicle emissions; motor vehicle product alterations, recalls, or advisories; performance monitoring of motor vehicles, motor vehicle parts and dealers; motor vehicle market research activities, including survey research; and removal of non-owner records from the original owner records of motor vehicle manufacturers; or\n            \t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t* for bulk distribution for surveys, marketing or solicitations if the State has obtained the express consent of the person to whom such personal information pertains.","terms":[],"answers":[{"answer_sub_graph_id":"[#81]","text":"yes"},{"answer_sub_graph_id":"[#82]","text":"no"}],"id":"DPPA8","type":"AskNode"},{"question":"Were the data obtained for use in research activities?","terms":[],"answers":[{"answer_sub_graph_id":"[#80]","text":"yes"},{"answer_sub_graph_id":"DPPA8","text":"no"}],"id":"DPPA7","type":"AskNode"},{"question":"Was consent obtained from the individuals whose information is contained in the data by the requester of the records?","terms":[],"answers":[{"answer_sub_graph_id":"DPPA6a","text":"yes"},{"answer_sub_graph_id":"DPPA7","text":"no"}],"id":"DPPA6","type":"AskNode"},{"question":"Was consent obtained from the person about whom the information pertains by the State DMV in response to a request for an individual record?","terms":[],"answers":[{"answer_sub_graph_id":"DPPA5a","text":"yes"},{"answer_sub_graph_id":"DPPA6","text":"no"}],"id":"DPPA5","type":"AskNode"},{"question":"Is the disclosure of these records made in accordance with the driver's license record disclosure law of the state from which the records were obtained?","terms":[],"answers":[{"answer_sub_graph_id":"[#75]","text":"no"},{"answer_sub_graph_id":"DPPA5","text":"yes"}],"id":"DPPA4","type":"AskNode"},{"question":"Is disclosure of the personal information required by the Driver's Privacy Protection Act? Disclosure is required, among other reasons, in connection with matters of motor vehicle or driver safety and theft; motor vehicle emissions; motor vehicle product alterations, recalls, or advisories; and performance monitoring of motor vehicles and dealers by motor vehicle manufacturers.","terms":[],"answers":[{"answer_sub_graph_id":"[#74]","text":"yes"},{"answer_sub_graph_id":"DPPA4","text":"no"}],"id":"DPPA3","type":"AskNode"},{"question":"Do the department of motor vehicles records contain an individual's photograph or image, Social Security number, or medical or disability information?","terms":[],"answers":[{"answer_sub_graph_id":"DPPA2a","text":"yes"},{"answer_sub_graph_id":"[#73]","text":"no"}],"id":"DPPA2","type":"AskNode"},{"question":"Do the data contain personal information obtained from a state department of motor vehicles?","terms":[{"term":"Personal information","explanation":"Information that identifies an individual, including, but not limited to, an individual's photograph, Social Security number, driver identification number, name, address [not including the 5-digit ZIP code], telephone number, or medical or disability information. It does not include information on vehicular accidents, driving violations, or a driver's status (including whether the driver's license is valid, suspended, or revoked)"}],"answers":[{"answer_sub_graph_id":"DPPA2","text":"yes"},{"answer_sub_graph_id":"[#83]","text":"no"}],"id":"DPPA1","type":"AskNode"}],"edges":[{"source":"DPPA1","target":"DPPA2"},{"source":"DPPA2","target":"DPPA2a"},{"source":"DPPA2a","target":"[#71]"},{"source":"[#71]","target":"[#83]"},{"source":"DPPA2a","target":"[#72]"},{"source":"DPPA2","target":"[#73]"},{"source":"[#73]","target":"DPPA3"},{"source":"DPPA3","target":"[#74]"},{"source":"[#74]","target":"[#83]"},{"source":"DPPA3","target":"DPPA4"},{"source":"DPPA4","target":"[#75]"},{"source":"DPPA4","target":"DPPA5"},{"source":"DPPA5","target":"DPPA5a"},{"source":"DPPA5a","target":"[#76]"},{"source":"[#76]","target":"[#83]"},{"source":"DPPA5a","target":"[#77]"},{"source":"[#77]","target":"[#83]"},{"source":"DPPA5","target":"DPPA6"},{"source":"DPPA6","target":"DPPA6a"},{"source":"DPPA6a","target":"[#78]"},{"source":"[#78]","target":"[#83]"},{"source":"DPPA6a","target":"[#79]"},{"source":"[#79]","target":"[#83]"},{"source":"DPPA6","target":"DPPA7"},{"source":"DPPA7","target":"[#80]"},{"source":"[#80]","target":"[#83]"},{"source":"DPPA7","target":"DPPA8"},{"source":"DPPA8","target":"[#81]"},{"source":"[#81]","target":"[#83]"},{"source":"DPPA8","target":"[#82]"},{"source":"DPPA1","target":"[#83]"}]},"govRecsCompliance":{"nodes":[{"id":"govRecsCompliance","type":"CallNode","CalleeId":"Gov1"},{"id":"[#56]","type":"CallNode","CalleeId":"DPPA1"},{"id":"[#57]","type":"EndNode"}],"edges":[{"source":"govRecsCompliance","target":"[#56]"},{"source":"[#56]","target":"[#57]"}]},"ferpaCompliance":{"nodes":[{"id":"[#40]","type":"EndNode"},{"id":"[#41]","type":"EndNode"},{"assignments":[{"Legal":[{"EducationRecords":[{"FERPA":["deidentified"]}]}]},{"Assertions":[{"DataType":[{"Harm":"minimal"},{"Effort":"deidentified"}]}]},{"Handling":[{"Transit":"clear"},{"Storage":"clear"}]},{"Code":"green"}],"id":"[#42]","type":"setNode"},{"id":"[#43]","type":"EndNode"},{"assignments":[{"Legal":[{"EducationRecords":[{"FERPA":["directoryOptOut"]}]}]},{"Assertions":[{"DataType":[{"Harm":"shame"},{"Effort":"identifiable"}]}]},{"Handling":[{"Transit":"encrypt"},{"Storage":"serverEncrypt"}]},{"Code":"yellow"}],"id":"[#44]","type":"setNode"},{"id":"[#46]","type":"EndNode"},{"assignments":[{"Legal":[{"EducationRecords":[{"FERPA":["directoryInfo"]}]}]},{"Assertions":[{"DataType":[{"Harm":"minimal"},{"Effort":"identifiable"}]}]},{"Code":"green"}],"id":"[#45]","type":"setNode"},{"question":"Did any of the students in the data, or their parents, if the students are under 18, request to opt out of the release of their information as directory information?","terms":[],"answers":[{"answer_sub_graph_id":"[#44]","text":"yes"},{"answer_sub_graph_id":"[#45]","text":"no"}],"id":"ferpa11a","type":"AskNode"},{"assignments":[{"Legal":[{"EducationRecords":[{"FERPA":["consent"]}]}]},{"Assertions":[{"DataType":[{"Harm":"shame"},{"Effort":"identifiable"}]}]},{"Handling":[{"Transit":"encrypt"}]},{"Code":"yellow"}],"id":"[#47]","type":"setNode"},{"id":"[#48]","text":"Consent sub-routine","type":"TodoNode"},{"id":"[#55]","type":"EndNode"},{"assignments":[{"Legal":[{"EducationRecords":[{"FERPA":["schoolOfficial"]}]}]},{"Assertions":[{"DataType":[{"Harm":"shame"},{"Effort":"identifiable"}]}]},{"Handling":[{"Transit":"encrypt"}]},{"Code":"yellow"}],"id":"[#49]","type":"setNode"},{"assignments":[{"Legal":[{"EducationRecords":[{"FERPA":["study"]}]}]},{"Assertions":[{"DataType":[{"Harm":"shame"},{"Effort":"identifiable"}]}]},{"Handling":[{"Transit":"encrypt"}]},{"Code":"yellow"}],"id":"[#50]","type":"setNode"},{"id":"[#51]","text":"DUA subroutine","type":"TodoNode"},{"assignments":[{"Legal":[{"EducationRecords":[{"FERPA":["audit"]}]}]},{"Assertions":[{"DataType":[{"Harm":"shame"},{"Effort":"identifiable"}]}]},{"Handling":[{"Transit":"encrypt"}]},{"Code":"yellow"}],"id":"[#52]","type":"setNode"},{"id":"[#53]","text":"DUA subroutine","type":"TodoNode"},{"reason":"An educational agency or institution is likely breaching its FERPA duties because it is disclosing, or a third party is re-disclosing, non-directory PII without parental consent where no obvious FERPA exception applies.","id":"[#54]","type":"RejectNode"},{"question":"Are the data being disclosed for the purpose of conducting an audit or evaluation of a federal- or state-supported education program?","terms":[{"term":"Education program","explanation":"Refers to a program principally engaged in the provision of education, including, but not limited to, early childhood education, elementary and secondary education, postsecondary education, special education, job training, career and technical education, and adult education, and any program that is administered by an educational agency or institution."}],"answers":[{"answer_sub_graph_id":"[#52]","text":"yes"},{"answer_sub_graph_id":"[#54]","text":"no"}],"id":"ferpa15","type":"AskNode"},{"question":"Are the data being disclosed for the purpose of conducting a study for, or on behalf of, the educational agency or institution in order to develop, validate, or administer predictive tests, or improve instruction?","terms":[],"answers":[{"answer_sub_graph_id":"[#50]","text":"yes"},{"answer_sub_graph_id":"ferpa15","text":"no"}],"id":"ferpa14","type":"AskNode"},{"question":"Are the data being disclosed to a school official or contractor with a legitimate educational interest?","terms":[{"term":"School official or contractor","explanation":"This includes professors; instructors; administrators; health staff; counselors; attorneys; clerical staff; trustees; members of committees and disciplinary boards; and contractors, consultants, volunteers or other parties to whom the school has outsourced institutional services or functions."},{"term":"Legitimate educational interest","explanation":"A school official generally has a legitimate educational interest if the official needs to review an education record in order to fulfill his or her professional responsibility. Legitimate educational interests include, but are not limited to, performing a task related to the regular duties of the employee or agent, the student\u2019s education, or a service or benefit for the student."}],"answers":[{"answer_sub_graph_id":"[#49]","text":"yes"},{"answer_sub_graph_id":"ferpa14","text":"no"}],"id":"ferpa13","type":"AskNode"},{"question":"Did the parents or guardians of the students, or the students themselves if they were adults or emancipated minors at the time of the data collection, provide written consent authorizing disclosure of their information?","terms":[{"term":"Written consent","explanation":"Refers to signed and dated written permission from the parents or students that specifies the records to be disclosed, the purpose of the disclosure, and to whom the records may be disclosed. The form of the consent and the other elements it may contain vary between institutions."}],"answers":[{"answer_sub_graph_id":"[#47]","text":"yes"},{"answer_sub_graph_id":"ferpa13","text":"no"}],"id":"ferpa12","type":"AskNode"},{"question":"Did the educational agency or institution designate all of the personally identifiable information in the data as directory information? The educational agency or institution provides notice to students and parents of the types of information it has designated as directory information.","terms":[{"term":"Directory information","explanation":"Refers to information that is generally not considered harmful or an invasion of privacy if released and can be disclosed to outside organizations without a parent's prior written consent.\n\n      * Types of information frequently designated as directory information include:\n      * Name, address, telephone listing, or e-mail address\n      * Photograph\n      * Date or place of birth\n      * Major field of study\n      * Dates of attendance\n      * Enrollment status, e.g., undergraduate or graduate, full-time or part-time\n      * Grade level or class year\n      * Participation in officially recognized activities and sports\n      * Height and weight of members of athletic teams\n      * Degrees, honors, and awards received\n      * Publication titles\n      * The most recent educational agency or institution attended\n\n      Directory information never includes a student\u2019s Social Security number or identification number that is used to access a student\u2019s education record."}],"answers":[{"answer_sub_graph_id":"ferpa11a","text":"yes"},{"answer_sub_graph_id":"ferpa12","text":"no"}],"id":"ferpa11","type":"AskNode"},{"question":"Do the data include personally identifiable information about a student? Personally identifiable information about a student includes, but is not limited to, the following categories of information:\n        * A student\u2019s name\n        * The name of a student\u2019s parent or other family members\n        * The address of a student or a student\u2019s family\n        * Other direct identifiers, defined as information that relates specifically to an individual, such as a student\u2019s Social Security number, student number, other identifying number or code, telephone number, e-mail address, or biometric record\n        * Other indirect identifiers, defined as information that can be combined with other information to identify specific individuals, such as the student\u2019s gender, race, religion, date of birth, place of birth, other geographic indicators, height, weight, mother\u2019s maiden name, activities, employment information, education information, financial information, and other descriptors\n        * Other information that, alone or in combination, is linked or linkable to a specific student that would allow a reasonable person in the school community, who does not have personal knowledge of the relevant circumstances, to identify the student with reasonable certainty\n        * Information disclosed in response to a targeted request","terms":[{"term":"Targeted request","explanation":"Refers to a request by a person who the educational agency or institution reasonably believes knows the identity of the student to whom the education record relates. For example, if there was a rumor published in the local paper that a public official was disciplined for cheating during his senior year in high school, a request to the high school for the disciplinary records of students who were caught cheating during the year the public official was a senior would be considered a targeted request."},{"term":"Biometric record","explanation":"Refers to a record of one or more measurable biological or behavioral characteristics that can be used for automated recognition of an individual. Examples include fingerprints; retina and iris patterns; voiceprints; DNA sequence; facial characteristics; and handwriting."},{"term":"Deidentified information","explanation":"Information that has been deidentified is considered not to contain personally identifiable information. The term deidentified is used to describe records that have enough personally identifiable information removed or obscured such that the remaining information does not identify an individual and there is no reasonable basis to believe that the information can be used to identify an individual. In making a determination that a student\u2019s identity is not personally identifiable, both single and multiple data releases from the education records should be taken into account along with other information available from other sources."}],"answers":[{"answer_sub_graph_id":"[#42]","text":"no"},{"answer_sub_graph_id":"ferpa11","text":"yes"}],"id":"ferpa10","type":"AskNode"},{"question":"Do the data contain any information derived from institutional records directly related to a student?\n         This refers to records maintained by an educational agency or institution, or by a person on behalf of the agency or institution, for each student in the normal course of business. For the purposes of this questionnaire, information may satisfy this definition even if it has been deidentified.\n\n         Examples of records directly related to a student include:\n\n          * Directory information such as name, address, telephone listing, e-mail address, date and place of birth, dates of attendance, number of course units in which enrolled, class level, major field of student, last school attended, degrees and honors received, participation in official student activities, and student athletes\u2019 weight and height\n          * Parent\u2019s or guardian\u2019s name or address\n          * Student identification number, Social Security number\n          * Demographic information such as gender, race, ethnicity, nationality, citizenship\n          * Identification photographs\n          * Current academic status, class schedule, courses taken, academic specialization and activities, units attempted and completed, instructors, past academic status, official communications regarding academic status\n          * Academic evaluations, including student examination papers, transcripts, grade point average, grades in courses, test scores, recorded communications that are part of the academic process, and other academic records\n          * Counseling and advising records\n          * Disciplinary records\n          * Financial aid records, including student loan collection records\n\n          Examples of records not directly related to a student include:\n\n          * Personal memory aids held in the sole possession of their creator, such as a teacher\u2019s notes\n          * Records maintained by the law enforcement division of an educational agency or institution\n          * Employment records for an educational agency or institution\n          * Records produced by a physician, psychiatrist, or other professional for treatment purposes\n          * Grades on peer-graded papers before a teacher has recorded them\n          * Records directly related to other individuals, such as records of teacher misconduct or complaints against school employees, that only tangentially refer to students\n          * Information obtained from observation and not from an education record ","terms":[],"answers":[{"answer_sub_graph_id":"[#41]","text":"no"},{"answer_sub_graph_id":"ferpa10","text":"yes"}],"id":"ferpa9","type":"AskNode"},{"question":"Do the data contain any information derived from records maintained by an educational agency or institution, or by a person or entity acting for the agency or institution, that receives funds from the US Department of Education?","terms":[{"term":"Educational agency or institution","explanation":"An educational agency or institution is a public or private agency or institution that provides educational services or instruction, or both, to students. This includes, but is not limited to, a primary or secondary school, college or university, school district, or state department of education."},{"term":"Funds from the US Department of Education","explanation":"This means funds provided for any purpose, research or otherwise, by the US Department of Education to the educational agency or institution. It includes funds provided by grant, cooperative agreement, contract, sub-grant, or subcontract; or funds provided to students attending the agency or institution. The funds may be paid to the institution by those students for educational purposes, such as under the Pell Grant Program and the Guaranteed Student Loan Program. This includes all public schools and a majority of private institutions, though most private and parochial schools at the elementary and secondary levels do not receive such funding."}],"answers":[{"answer_sub_graph_id":"[#40]","text":"no"},{"answer_sub_graph_id":"ferpa9","text":"yes"}],"id":"ferpaCompliance","type":"AskNode"}],"edges":[{"source":"ferpaCompliance","target":"[#40]"},{"source":"ferpaCompliance","target":"ferpa9"},{"source":"ferpa9","target":"[#41]"},{"source":"ferpa9","target":"ferpa10"},{"source":"ferpa10","target":"[#42]"},{"source":"[#42]","target":"[#43]"},{"source":"ferpa10","target":"ferpa11"},{"source":"ferpa11","target":"ferpa11a"},{"source":"ferpa11a","target":"[#44]"},{"source":"[#44]","target":"[#46]"},{"source":"ferpa11a","target":"[#45]"},{"source":"[#45]","target":"[#46]"},{"source":"ferpa11","target":"ferpa12"},{"source":"ferpa12","target":"[#47]"},{"source":"[#47]","target":"[#48]"},{"source":"[#48]","target":"[#55]"},{"source":"ferpa12","target":"ferpa13"},{"source":"ferpa13","target":"[#49]"},{"source":"[#49]","target":"ferpa14"},{"source":"ferpa14","target":"[#50]"},{"source":"[#50]","target":"[#51]"},{"source":"[#51]","target":"ferpa15"},{"source":"ferpa15","target":"[#52]"},{"source":"[#52]","target":"[#53]"},{"source":"[#53]","target":"[#55]"},{"source":"ferpa15","target":"[#54]"},{"source":"ferpa14","target":"ferpa15"},{"source":"ferpa13","target":"ferpa14"}]},"[#1]":{"nodes":[{"assignments":[{"Code":"green"}],"id":"[#2]","type":"setNode"},{"id":"[#3]","type":"CallNode","CalleeId":"medicalRecordsCompliance"},{"id":"[#4]","type":"CallNode","CalleeId":"ppraCompliance"},{"id":"[#5]","type":"CallNode","CalleeId":"ferpaCompliance"},{"id":"[#6]","type":"CallNode","CalleeId":"govRecsCompliance"},{"id":"[#7]","text":"Arrest and Conviction Records, Bank and Financial Records,\n        Cable Television, Computer Crime,\n        Credit reporting and Investigations (including 'Credit Repair', 'Credit Clinics', Check-Cashing and Credit Cards),\n        Criminal Justice Information Systems, Electronic Surveillance (including Wiretapping, Telephone Monitoring, and Video Cameras),\n        Employment Records, Government Information on Individuals, Identity Theft,\n        Insurance Records (including use of Genetic Information), Library Records,\n        Mailing Lists (including Video rentals and Spam),\n        Special Medical Records (including HIV Testing),\n        Non-Electronic Visual Surveillance. Breast-Feeding, Polygraphing in Employment,\n        Privacy Statutes\/State Constitutions (including the Right to Publicity),\n        Privileged Communications, Social Security Numbers, Student Records, Tax Records,\n        Telephone Services (including Telephone Solicitation and Caller ID),\n        Testing in Employment (including Urinalysis, Genetic and Blood Tests), Tracking Technologies,  Voter Records","type":"TodoNode"},{"id":"[#9]","type":"CallNode","CalleeId":"dua"},{"id":"[#10]","type":"EndNode"},{"assignments":[{"Assertions":[{"Identity":"noPersonData"}]},{"Code":"blue"}],"id":"[#8]","type":"setNode"},{"question":"Do the data concern living persons?","terms":[],"answers":[{"answer_sub_graph_id":"[#2]","text":"yes"},{"answer_sub_graph_id":"[#8]","text":"no"}],"id":"[#1]","type":"AskNode"}],"edges":[{"source":"[#1]","target":"[#2]"},{"source":"[#2]","target":"[#3]"},{"source":"[#3]","target":"[#4]"},{"source":"[#4]","target":"[#5]"},{"source":"[#5]","target":"[#6]"},{"source":"[#6]","target":"[#7]"},{"source":"[#7]","target":"[#9]"},{"source":"[#9]","target":"[#10]"},{"source":"[#1]","target":"[#8]"},{"source":"[#8]","target":"[#9]"}]}},"title":"questionnaire.dg"}